

# ALIYA MOHAMED

#### LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Java, C++, Python\*, SQL\*, HTML\*, CSS\*, React and Redux\*, Express\*, MongoDB\*, Meteor\*
- Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, STATA Statistical Software, REDCap, Microsoft Office Tools, Teleform

\*currently learning

#### **PROJECTS**

#### ShortList (May-Aug 2019)

- Full stack web application for users to interactively manage and organize job applications. Users visualize job application status, track dates in a calendar and upload documents
- React, Redux, Meteor, MongoDB and deployed with Heroku

#### Messages Webpage (May-Aug 2019)

- Full stack message list website
- React, Redux, Express, MongoDB and deployed with Heroku

#### **Non-Inclusive Language Detector (Apr 2019)**

- Chrome extension which highlights words or phrases which are oppressive in the Canadian context. Informed by the University of Calgary's Inclusive Language Guide (2017)
- · HTML, CSS and JavaScript

#### Task Manager List (Jan-Apr 2019)

- Application where users can input time, deadlines and tags in separate input fields or in single input field to be parsed
- Java and JavaFX

#### **HACKATHONS**

## HackUBC: Learning Analytics and Canvas API Hackathon (Mar 2019)

 Attended workshops on topics such as product ideation and design, data visualization. Learned about Python, Jupyter notebooks and APIs

#### cmd-f (Feb 2019)

 Created a visual productivity app in a group of five for users to keep track of time spent on various tasks and set goals in time bubbles. Organized, created and implemented classes in Java. Used JavaFX Scene Builder to build UI

#### **UBC Local Hack Day (Dec 2018)**

 Worked as part of a team of 4 to make a language focused app for newcomers to Canada to learn colloquial phrases for everyday use. My role was mainly to help establish and dissect issues with the conceptual idea and format, as well as prepare the prototype for presentation

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of British Columbia** Sep 2018 – Jan 2021

- Currently enrolled with 4<sup>th</sup> year standing
- Bachelor of Computer Science (BCS)

### University of Calgary

Sep 2013 - Apr 2018

- Bachelor of Science, Biological Sciences
- Bachelor of Arts, Sociology
- Distinction (GPA 3.8)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Research Assistant May – Sep of 2018, 2017, 2016

Alberta Health Services - Cancer Epidemiology and Prevention Research

- Updated a systematic review and meta-analysis that led to a publication
- Produced video content for website
- Developed a survey instrument with REDCap and analyzed results using STATA 13.1 for 522 participants
- data entry and cleaning for upwards of 1000 participants

**Teaching Assistant Aug 2012 – Aug 2018** 

**KUMON Learning Services** 

#### **EXTRACURRICULARS**

#### Committee Member Feb 2019 – Present

Computer Science Committee for Outreach, Diversity, and Equity (CODE)

Volunteer

Sep 2018 - Apr 2019

**UBC** Ismaili Students Association

Volunteer

**Apr 2017 - Aug 2018** 

Brenda Stafford Society for the Prevention of Domestic Violence